Ryan McClure

(925) 457-8887

ryanwademcclure@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Four years leadership experience in the Marine Corps. Highly motivated and quick learner. Experience with communicating appropriately with clients, points of contact, and able to handle work in a fast paced environment. Able to operate in a changing environment and adapt accordingly.

Honorably discharged in June of 2016 from the US Marine Corps and began community college soon after to pursue a degree in the Computer Science field. I have been on the honor roll every semester and maintained an average GPA of 3.75.

Starting in Fall of 2018 I transferred to UC San Diego to finish my BS in Computer Science. Current average GPA of 3.414.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Leadership
- Adaptability

SKILLS

- Proficient in C/C++
- Experience using Git
- Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures

- Self Motivated
- Customer Service
- Basic linux command line experience
- Ability to plan and schedule ahead
- Proficient using Microsoft Office

Extracurricular

Software Team Member, Yonder Dynamics, UCSD, 2018-present

Yonder Dynamics is UC San Diego's premier robotics organization for undergraduates
that focuses on designing and building autonomous rovers for terrestrial exploration.
Every year, we compete in the University Rover Challenge, a prestigious international
competition that challenges teams to design and build a rover that would be of use to

- early explorers on Mars. Our primary purpose is to empower undergraduates to work in robotics, space, and related fields, regardless of their age and major, or other circumstances. We believe in developing individuals from the ground up to prepare them for their future endeavors.
- Since joining Yonder in the fall of 2018, I have worked on projects like implementing an Extended Kalman Filter, and sensor fusion, for the purposes of dealing with the robots navigational abilities.

Employment History

Outside Services Attendant, Roundhill Country Club, Alamo, CA, 2017-2018

 The Outside Services Attendant is responsible for providing carts and range balls for Members and guests while keeping all work areas clean, orderly, and safe. They greet Members and guests in a friendly and courteous manner while projecting a professional image. The Outside Services Attendant communicates in a clear and professional manner information that assists the Members and guests in playing the course.

Corporal, United States Marine Corps, Camp Pendleton, CA, 2012-2016

- MOS 0351 Infantry Assaultman
 - Experience in tactical employment by using rockets, the Anti-Personnel Obstacle Breaching System (APOBS), and demolitions (C4) against fortified positions in support of rifle squads, platoons, and companies within an infantry battalion. Utilized breaching/infiltration techniques to facilitate infantry maneuver in the offense, and expedient counter mobility measures in the defense.
- USMC Team Leader
 - Supervised over 20 personnel in special work groups ensuring completion of assigned tasks.
 - Maintained records for 40 Marines for a year and a half
 - Ensured quality in performance of my team
- Other Marine Corps Duties
 - Instructed US Marines and foreign forces in numerous tactical applications in the Middle East, including the Royal Jordanian Marines in IED detection.
 - Maintained security of USMC outpost in Jordan, protecting over 200 lives and millions of dollars of equipment.

Parking Lot Attendant, Sanderson Enterprises, Hampton Beach, New Hampshire, 2011

• Handled thousands of dollars every day.

- Maintained security on over 100 vehicles daily.
- Dealt with customers in a courteous and professional fashion with zero complaints.

Office Clerk, Law Office of Sally Elkington, Oakland, CA 2009

- Organized and prepared countless cases for the resident attorneys.
- Scanned, emailed, and faxed documents
- Utilized legal software
- Coordinated with office paralegals
- Detailed record keeping of thousands of legal cases.

Education and Training

- Advanced Leadership and Ethics Course USS Anchorage
 - Learned numerous skills such as conflict resolution, mentoring, counseling, morals, ethics, pride, esprit de corps, team building, and motivating both peers and subordinates.
- Combat Rubber Reconnaissance Craft Repair Course- Coronado, CA
 - Learned skills in repairing industrial rubber on an inflatable watercraft. Learned how to maintain and repair a two stroke 55 horsepower Evinrude engine for the boats. Repairs were done both in the shop and on the water during a mission.
- Infantry Assaultman Course- Camp Pendleton, CA
 - Experience in tactical employment by using rockets, the Anti-Personnel Obstacle Breaching System (APOBS), and demolitions (C4) against fortified positions in support of rifle squads, platoons, and companies within an infantry battalion. Utilized breaching/infiltration techniques to facilitate infantry maneuver in the offense, and expedient counter mobility measures in the defense.
- Basic Infantryman Course- Camp Pendleton, CA
- Recruit Training- San Diego, CA
 - Learned basic military skills such as first aid, land navigation, marksmanship, physical fitness, and self defense.
- High School Diploma- College Park High School, Pleasant Hill, CA